翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
使用AI工具翻译，如有不准确的地方请在弹幕或评论区指正，谢谢！
Self driving cars have been an engineers dream for a long time.
自动驾驶汽车长久以来一直是工程师们的梦想
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
In this video made by General Motors in the 1950s,
在这段由通用汽车公司于1950年代制作的视频中
it shows a the car of the future driving a family on a road trip using something called "autopilot."
展示了一辆未来的汽车通过名为“自动驾驶”的技术载着一家人进行公路旅行
Only in this concept, the car is controlled by a tower with a human making the decisions,
在这一理念中，汽车由一座塔台控制，由人类做出决策
similar to air traffic control. If you haven't watched this video,
类似于空中交通管制。如果你还没看过这个视频
it's actually out there on YouTube. In fact I'll put a link down in the description for it
这段视频其实就在YouTube上。我会在简介附上它的链接
It's actually really fascinating to see what people back then thought that the future was going to be like.
看到过去的人们对未来模样的设想，实在是件非常有趣的事
Personally, it looks like the biggest thing they misunderstood is exactly how much traffic that
就我个人而言，他们最大的误解似乎在于严重低估了
we were going to have. Of course growing up, Hollywood continued to
我们将会面临的交通规模。随着这一概念的发展好莱坞不断
tease the idea that someday cars would be able to drive themselves, such as Kitt from Knight rider,
暗示未来某天汽车能够自动驾驶的想法，比如《霹雳游侠》中的基特
or the Johnny cab from Total Recall,
《全面回忆》里的约翰尼出租车
or Lenina Huxley's police car from Demolition man which
或是《超级战警》里蕾妮娜·赫胥莉的警车
by the way made an appearance in Seaquest DSV as well,
顺带一提，这辆车还在《深海巡弋》中露过脸
its one of many technologies us kids believed would be around when we grew up, along with flying cars,
这是我们这些孩子曾经深信长大后会出现众多技术之一，比如飞行汽车
giant space station hotels, or colonies on the moon. Or, for that matter artificial intelligence.
巨大的太空站酒店，或是月球上的殖民地。当然，还包括人工智能
I'm afraid I can't do that
我恐怕办不到
And while I am disappointed
尽管我对我们尚未在月球上建立殖民地，没有飞行汽车这类东西感到失望
that we don't have colonies on the moon and flying cars and stuff like that,
I can at least say that I have talked to an artificial intelligence
我至少可以说，我能和人工智能交谈了
and ridden in a self-driving car. Two things that if
并且坐过自动驾驶汽车。这两件事
you'd asked me a couple of years ago, I would say I would probably never experience in my lifetime.
如果几年前你问我，我会说我这辈子可能都不会体验到
And there are two primary reasons that I wanted to make this video. The first is, I just find
我想制作这个视频主要有两个原因。首先，我只是
the technology fascinating and interesting. But,
觉得这项技术既迷人又有趣。但是
the other reason is because when I watch
另一个原因是，当我在YouTube甚至主流新闻上看这些视频时，它们经常误报或曲解
these videos on YouTube and even on the mainstream news they're often misreporting or misrepresenting
另一个原因是，当我在YouTube甚至主流新闻上观看这些视频时，它们经常误报或曲解
it's full self-driving, especially when it comes to Tesla.
“全自动驾驶”的概念，尤其是在涉及特斯拉的时候
They're often saying that it doesn't work,
他们总说这行不通，
it's never going to work, and it's some kind of investor scam, or or so on and so forth,
这根本不会成功，就是某种投资骗局，诸如此类的说法
which is just at odds with my personal experience. And so I just felt compelled
这与我个人的经历完全不符，因此我深感
to show the world what I've experienced.
有必要向世界展示我所经历的一切
So, first I want to introduce you to my car, and give you some general information about it.
首先，我想向你介绍一下我的车，并告诉你一些关于它的基本信息
This is Smurf. I bought it two years ago.
这是蓝精灵。我两年前买的
It came in the standard white color, but I didn't care much for any of Tesla's factory colors,
它原来是标准白色，但我对特斯拉工厂提供的任何颜色都不太感冒
so I had it wrapped this way. Now, while I think it looks awesome, I'm well aware that the color
所以我把它包成这样。虽然我觉得看起来很棒，但我也很清楚这个配色方案
scheme is polarizing. If I were to make a graph of the number of people that love or hate it,
会引起两极分化的反应。如果要统计喜欢和讨厌它的人数
it would look something like this, with almost nobody falling in the middle.
看上去会是这样，几乎没有人落在中间
But, I can say that everyone notices it. And I am the only one with this color scheme to my knowledge.
不过，可以说所有人注意到了这一点。据我所知，我是唯一拥有这种配色的人
I'd also like to interject here that I also realize that Tesla and of course Elon Musk
我还想插一句，我也意识到特斯拉，当然还有埃隆·马斯克
are controversial topics at this stage. And, I just want to make it clear that
现阶段都是颇具争议的话题。我只想明确表示
I started this video back in 2024, It has no political objective, I am not taking sides on the issue.
这段视频始于2024年，它没有任何政治目的，我对此问题不持立场
This is just an objective look at a piece of fascinating technology. Now granted the video
这仅仅是对一项引人入胜的技术进行客观审视。当然，视频主要聚焦于特斯拉
focuses mostly on Tesla because
that's what I have access to and that's what I have experience with,
因为我拥有实物，我也具备一些经验
but don't read anything more into it than what I said: an objective look at technology.
但不要过度解读我的话：这只是对技术的一种客观审视
I also feel like self-driving in general, whether it be by Tesla or Waymo, or anyone else
我也觉得，无论是特斯拉、Waymo还是其他公司的自动驾驶技术
gets villified in the news. And what we're seeing is something called "Selection Bias."
在新闻中普遍受到了妖魔化。我们所看到的其实是一种被称为“选择性偏差”的现象
I want to give you an example of how this works. So, let's imagine a car, could be a chevrolet,
我想给你举个例子说明这是什么。假设有一辆车，可能是雪佛兰
maybe a Ford, or a Jeep. Doesn't really matter which brand it is. If it catches on fire,
也许是福特，或是吉普。具体什么品牌并不重要。如果它着火了
then the fire department shows up to put it out. Other than that, nobody cares.
然后消防队赶来把火扑灭。除此之外，没人在乎
If a Tesla, or really any sort of electric vehicle, catches fire then the fire department shows up too. But
如果一辆特斯拉，或者任何类型的电动车起火，消防部门会赶到现场
you also get a news van, a few news helicopters, another news van, etc. And of course this becomes
但同时还会引来新闻转播车、几架新闻直升机、又一辆新闻转播车等等
front page news all over the world leading to headlines like these and of course all over social media.
当然，这就会成为全球的头版新闻，类似这样的头条，当然也会在社交媒体上疯传
And while everyone understands that EV fires are harder to put out than traditional cars,
尽管所有人都明白，电动汽车起火比传统汽车更难扑灭
this sort of selection bias leads some people to believe that Teslas or EVs in general
这种选择性偏差让一些人误以为特斯拉或电动汽车总体上
catch fire more often than gasoline cars, despite the fact that the opposite is actually true.
比汽油车更容易起火，尽管事实恰恰相反
Unfortunately, self driving cars are subject to the same news selection bias,
不幸的是，自动驾驶汽车同样受到新闻选择偏见的左右
so anytime there is an accident with one of these systems it is front page news,
因此，每当这些系统发生事故时，都会成为头版新闻
again, leading a lot of people to believe these systems are inherently unsafe, or that they don't work.
这让许多人再次认为这些系统本质上就不安全，或者根本不起作用
And so I wanted to set the record straight with this video.
因此我想通过这个视频澄清事实
SO, back to Smurf for a moment. This is a base,
那么，再简单说一下蓝精灵。这是一辆基础版的
standard range model-3. It has the LFP battery pack,
标准续航Model 3，搭载了LFP电池组
which I specifically wanted. It has a range of 272 miles, and a zero to 60 time of around 5.6 seconds.
我特意选择的。它的续航里程为272英里，0到60英里/小时加速时间约为5.6秒
约438公里
约0到96公里/小时
It was literally the cheapest brand new Tesla I could buy,
这确实是我能买到的最便宜的全新特斯拉了
and after the tax incentives it wound up costing me around $31,000.
在享受税收优惠后，最终花费了我大约31,000美元
Which I think is rather amusing because when I have shown this car in previous videos I've
我觉得这挺有意思的，因为之前我在视频里展示这辆车时
always seen comments saying things to the effect of, "look at David trying to flaunt his wealth"
总能看到类似这样的评论：“瞧瞧大卫，又想炫富了”
or "driving such an ostentatious vehicle" or something of that nature which I find
或者“开着这么招摇的车”之类的话，我觉得这特别奇怪
so bizarre because, you know, I paid approximately the same price as buying like a Toyota Camry or
因为你知道，我花的钱大概和买一辆丰田凯美瑞差不多
something like that, and nobody would have said that about me had I been driving around in a Toyota Camry.
要是我开的是丰田凯美瑞，就没人会这么说了
And part of the reason I bring this up is because I wanted people to understand
我之所以提到这一点，部分原因是希望人们明白
that the technology I'm about to show is consumer level technology.
我即将展示的技术属于消费级技术
This is not something that you have to spend $100,000 in order to experience.
这并非需要花费十万美元才能体验的事情
The first thing I need to explain is difference between Autopilot and FSD, which is short for full self driving.
首先要解释的是自动驾驶辅助和全自动驾驶之间的区别
These are two entirely different things.
这是两件完全不同的事
The media often gets it wrong when reporting on this.
媒体在报道此事时经常出错
Even Mark Rober, who is one of my favorite Youtubers by the way,
顺便说一句，马克·罗伯特也是我最喜欢的Youtuber之一
got it wrong when he made a video titled "can you fool a self driving car."
他在制作题为“你能骗过自动驾驶汽车吗”的视频时搞错了
In this video, he sets up a Wylie Coyote style wall and has his tesla drive straight through.
在这段视频中，他设置了一面怀尔·E·科约特风格的墙，并让他的特斯拉直接穿了过去
The trouble is, in the video, he's using autopilot, not FSD.
问题在于，视频中他使用的是自动驾驶辅助功能，而非全自动驾驶系统
So we're actually going to talk more about Mark Rober's video later in this video.
我们稍后在这段视频中会进一步讨论马克·罗伯的视频内容
So what is the difference? Autopilot is really nothing more than a fancy adaptive cruise control.
那么区别在哪里呢？自动驾驶充其量不过是一种高级的自适应巡航控制
When it first came out in 2014,
当它在2014年首次问世时
it was really the best in its class. But to be honest, there are plenty of cars on the road
它确实是同级产品中的佼佼者。但说实话，如今道路上有很多车辆的
today that have adaptive cruise control similar or even better than autopilot.
自适应巡航控制系统已经与自动驾驶仪不相上下，甚至更胜一筹
For example, this is my brother's Ford F150, which is equipped with blue cruise. As you can see,
例如，这是我兄弟的福特F150，它配备了BlueCruise自动驾驶系统。正如你所见
it even offers a hands-free option, which seems to work pretty well. It also had not one,
它甚至提供了解放双手选项，效果似乎相当不错。而且还不止一个，
but two cameras watching the driver, one here and the other one over here.
摄像头监视着司机，一个在这里，另一个在那里
However, this system only works on the highway, and only on certain highways at that.
然而，该系统仅适用于高速公路，而且还仅限于特定的高速公路路段
It will not drive you around in town.
它不会在城里载着你到处跑
That being said, bluecruise is considered more advanced than Tesla's autopilot.
话虽如此，bluecruise被认为比特斯拉的自动驾驶系统更为先进
But just so we're clear, all Tesla Autopilot does is maintain your speed,
但为了明确起见，特斯拉自动驾驶系统的功能仅限于保持车速
keep you from hitting the car in front of you, and keep you centered in your lane.
防止与前车相撞以及将车辆维持在车道中央
That is, assuming your lane doesn't turn too sharply, like with this guy.
也就是说，假设你所在的车道没有像这位老兄那样急转弯
It's pretty handy in stop and go traffic. And much like any cruise control, it's also handy on the freeway. But,
在走走停停的车流中相当实用。与任何定速巡航系统类似，它在高速公路上也很方便
just like any cruise control you need to keep your hands on the wheel
但就像任何巡航控制一样，你需要随时把手放在方向盘上
and be ready to take over if something happens.
准备好应对突发情况
We've probably all seen the news stories about autopilot related crashes.
我们可能都看过有关自动驾驶相关车祸的新闻报道
There are people who blame Tesla, and have even attempted to sue Tesla
有人指责特斯拉，甚至试图因这些有时致命的事故起诉特斯拉
for these sometimes deadly crashes. And while it
makes for a good news story, a more objective way to look at it would be this.
虽然这能成为一则吸引眼球的新闻，但更客观的看法应该是这样的
If the same accident had occurred in a different brand of vehicle, like a Ford or Chevrolet with an equivelant
如果同样的意外发生在另一品牌车辆上，比如配备类似巡航控制系统的福特或雪佛兰
cruise control system, nobody would be blaming the car manufacturer, they'd be blaming the driver.
没人会指责汽车制造商，他们只会责怪司机
Let's face it, if the news media started reporting on "cruise control" related crashes,
说实话，如果新闻媒体开始报道与“定速巡航”相关的事故
then nobody would really care. The term Autopilot is just far better clickbait than cruise control.
根本没人会真正在意。相比“定速巡航”，“自动驾驶”这个术语显然更能吸引点击
FSD is an entirely different software package for your Tesla.
全自动驾驶是专为特斯拉打造的一套完全不同的软件套件
To drive the point home, a good analogy would be this.
为了更清楚地说明这一点，可以用一个恰当的类比来解释
If Autopilot is the equivalent of having MS-Paint on your computer,
如果自动驾驶相当于在你的电脑上安装了微软画图
then FSD would be like having photoshop. After you pay for and install FSD,
那么全自动驾驶就像是拥有了Photoshop。在你付费并安装全自动驾驶后
you'll immediately notice the appearance of the center screen is different.
你会立刻注意到中央屏幕的外观有所不同
Just for comparison, let's look at two different Teslas.
为了对比，我们来看两款不同的特斯拉汽车
This is my friend Sean's Tesla, he named his Skippy.
这是我朋友肖恩的特斯拉，他给它起名叫斯基皮
Smurf and Skippy actually spend a lot of time together, they're good friends.
蓝精灵和斯基皮其实经常待在一起，他们是很好的朋友
But Skippy is only equipped with autopilot. So what we're going to do
但斯基皮仅配备了自动驾驶功能。所以我们要做的是
is drive both cars to the same intersection and find out how each of them sees the world.
把两辆车开到同一个十字路口，看看它们各自是如何感知世界的
Here's what Skippy looks like with regular autopilot.
这是斯基皮在常规自动驾驶模式下的样子
It only cares about the lanes on either side of it, and what's directly in front.
它只关心两侧的车道和正前方的状况
Now let's see what Smurf sees with FSD at the same intersection.
现在让我们看看蓝精灵在同一个路口通过全自动驾驶看到了什么
You can see the level of detail is seriously impressive. It's tracking every car within sight.
细节处理的精细程度令人惊叹，它能追踪视野范围内的每一辆汽车
By the way, this is always on the screen even if you are driving the car manually.
顺便说一句，即使你手动驾驶汽车时，这个也会一直显示在屏幕上
So, this is one way to tell, when your watching a video, if the Tesla in question has autopilot or FSD.
所以，这是一种判断方法，当你在观看视频时，可以分辨出哪辆特斯拉是否配备了自动驾驶或全自动驾驶功能
Speaking of, how does it see so much? All Teslas are equipped with at least 8 cameras.
说到这个，它是如何看到这么多的？所有特斯拉都至少配备了8个摄像头
The main cameras are at the top of the windshield here. But there are also cameras on the
主摄像头位于挡风玻璃顶部这里。但前翼子板这里
front fenders here, and on the side pillars here. There are actually two cameras facing forward,
和侧柱这里也装有摄像头。实际上有两个摄像头朝向前方
a narrow view and a wide angle. Then you have the fender cameras looking somewhat backwards.
狭窄的视野与宽广的角度。接着是略微朝后看的挡板摄像头
then the side pillars, and of course the rear camera. And there's another camera inside the cabin that
然后是侧柱，当然还有后置摄像头。车厢内还有
is watching you. This way the car can monitor you and make sure you are watching the road.
另一个摄像头正注视着你。这样车辆就能监控你，确保你在关注路况
In fact, you actually preview all of the car's cameras on the
事实上，你可以在屏幕上预览这辆车的所有摄像头画面
screen, and this is the view it has to watch me. I always feel like somebody's watching me.
这就是它用来监控我的视角。我总感觉有人在盯着我
I always feel like somebody's watching me
我总感觉有人盯着我
该段歌曲：Sandro Puddu - Rock the Night (Original Mix)
Then of course there's the FSD computer, which uses a neural processor to handle
当然还有全自动驾驶计算机，它利用神经处理器来
all of the pattern recognition and decision making.
处理所有的模式识别和决策制定
Actually, you may notice this section of the board looks almost identical to this section.
实际上，你可能会注意到这块板子的这部分与那部分几乎一模一样
And that's not a coincidence. It's like two computers in one, both doing the same job.
这并非巧合。就像一台电脑里装了两台机器，同时执行着相同的任务
This is for redundancy in case one fails.
这是为了在其中一个失效时提供冗余保障
So, what we need to do now is find out, you know, how good is it? What can it do? What
所以，我们现在要做的是弄清楚它到底有多好？它能做什么？
can it not do? You know, is it safe? You know those type of things. So, I'm going
不能做什么？安全性如何？诸如此类的问题。那么，我接下来
to do my best to answer all of those questions.
尽我所能回答所有这些问题
So in order to answer the question of how good is Tesla's FSD,
因此为了回答特斯拉的全自动驾驶有多好的问题
we have to first define some sort of scale.
我们首先需要定义某种尺度
So this is the scale of driving perfection.
这是驾驶完美的尺度
It's nothing official, just something I came up with to illustrate a point.
这不算正式内容，只是我为了说明观点临时想出来的
And at one end, I'll use a banana to represent something that can't drive at all.
在一端，我会用香蕉来代表完全无法驾驶的东西
And then further up the scale maybe a chimpanzee.
再往上，或许是一只黑猩猩
And then we have a number of different types of human drivers, such as a drunk driver, sleepy driver,
接着我们还有多种不同类型的人类驾驶员，比如酒驾司机、疲劳驾驶司机
elderly driver, student driver,
老年司机，实习司机
and then eventually to a normal driver.
最终是一名普通司机
Now, notice that I don't have anything at the far end of perfection. That is
现在，请注意我并没有将任何东西放在完美的极端位置
because nothing currently exists that can go there. Even a good human driver makes
这是因为目前还没有任何事物能够达到那种境界。即便是优秀的人类驾驶员
mistakes from time to time, and thus there is no perfect driver. So, realistically,
也偶尔会犯错，因此不存在完美无缺的驾驶者。所以，现实地说，
for AI to take over driving, it doesn't have to be perfect. It only has to be as good as this guy!
要让AI接管驾驶，它不必做到完美无缺，只要和这家伙水平相当就够了！
So where do I rank Tesla's FSD? Well, a few years ago I would have put it somewhere down
那么特斯拉的全自动驾驶在我这儿排什么位置呢？几年前我可能会把它放在相当靠后的位置
here. But every few months they release a new update and it gets a little bit better,
但每隔几个月他们就会发布新版本，每次都会有所进步
and a little bit better. And this slow improvement has been going on for years. So where is it now?
并且稍微好了一点。这种缓慢的改进已经持续了多年。那么现在它在哪里呢？
Well, I think the easiest way to answer that is to just show you. So, I've decided to take
嗯，我觉得回答这个问题最简单的方式就是直接展示给你看。所以
a trip from my house to downtown Dallas and hopefully see the giant eyeball of Dallas.
我决定从我家出发去达拉斯市中心，希望能看到达拉斯那个巨大的眼球雕塑
And I've invided David Lovett from the youtube channel Usagi Electric to join me. In fact, here
我邀请了来自YouTube频道Usagi Electric的大卫·洛维特加入我
he is now, pulling up in his japanese right hand drive Nissan Cedric.
他来了，正开着他那辆右舵驾驶的日产Cedric缓缓驶来
And without wasting any time, he jumped in my car.
他二话没说就跳进了我的车
"it's nice."
“这很棒”
OK, so I've got David Lovitt here with me. I brought him in because I thought he would be
好的，现在我身边的是大卫·洛维特。我邀请他来是因为我觉得
the perfect passenger because he knows about computers, and you're an automotive expert!
他是最合适的乘客，因为他懂电脑，又是汽车专家！
Depends on the cutoff date for expert there. For most of my stuff is from the seventies. Anyway,
这取决于是什么时候的专家。我大部分的东西都是七十年代的
what we're going to do is, we have decided to go visit the giant eyeball of Dallas which is
不管怎样，我们接下来要做的是，去参观位于达拉斯市中心的那颗巨大的眼球
in the middle of downtown. That will give us a great opportunity to drive through suburban
这将为我们提供绝佳机会驶过郊区居民区、高速公路，当然还有市中心的车流
neighborhoods, the freeway, and of course downtown traffic.
Or I say we, the car will do that for us,
或者我说我们，车子会替我们搞定一切
hopefully. so I'm going to go ahead and put in the address here, 1300 elm street is a parking garage.
希望如此。那么我就直接在这里输入地址了，埃尔姆街130号是一个停车场
As you can see, we've got a long way to go. Says it's going to be 38 minutes.
如你所见，我们还有很长的路要走。显示还需要38分钟
！安全驾驶，遵守交通法规，时刻注意周围情况！
So here we go, I'm going to engage self drive. OOh.. that's akward and weird.
好的，我们开始吧，我要启动自动驾驶了。这感觉有点尴尬又奇怪
This is my first time ever in a self driving car. I think this is also my first time in a model 3, oh no, I rode in
这是我第一次坐自动驾驶汽车。我想这也是我第一次坐Model 3
Shane's model 3. But yeah, this is wild and weird.
不对，我坐过Shane的Model 3。不过确实，这感觉既新奇又怪异
he is. I can tell how nervous he is. This is so uncanny. and extremely nerve racking at first.
我能看出他有多紧张。这太诡异了。一开始让人神经紧绷
It's rally fascinating because when somebody
这真的非常奇妙，因为当有人在驾驶时
is driving you can feel the humanness of their inputs, but that's completely gone. I wouldn't
你能感受到他们操作中的人性化，但那种感觉完全消失了。我从未想过
have thought that I would be able to feel that.
自己竟能察觉到这种差异
After the first 10 minutes or so, I had yet to
大约10分钟后，我仍未触碰方向盘或踏板，而大卫·洛维特对此仍然相当紧张
touch the wheel or pedals and David Lovett was still pretty nervous about this, especially as
we were about to get on the interstate. I don't know how you trained your body
尤其是我们即将驶上州际公路。我不知道你是如何训练自己的身体
to not instinctively grab the steering wheel and like stand on the brake as you're coming
在接近红灯时能克制本能不去抓方向盘或猛踩刹车的。而我这边简直要把脚踩穿地板了
up to a stop light. I'm over here trying to push my foot through the floorboard.
Have you found that it's easier for your mind to wander if you're not actually part
你是否发现，如果自己并未真正参与驾驶过程，思想更容易开小差？
of the driving experience? yes, and no. So, I will say, that with the car driving itself,
可以说既是，也不是。所以我认为，当汽车自动驾驶时
I do vigalantly watch the road. In fact, I kind of have to. I guess I haven't told you yet, there's
我确实在警惕地观察着路面。实际上，某种程度上我必须这样做。我想我还没告诉你
a camera right there. Yeah. And It's watching me. And if it sees me pick up my phone and play on it,
那里有个摄像头。没错。它正盯着我。如果它看到我拿起手机玩的话
or if it sees me looking away from the road for more than just a few seconds, it will actually
或者如果它发现我的视线离开路面超过几秒钟，屏幕上就会开始显示警告
start complaining on the screen. and if I don't stop it will say please pay attention to the road.
如果我不立即停止，它还会提示“请注意看路”
if I don't stop doing that, it will start beeping at me and eventually it will disengage.
如果我不停止这么做，它就会开始对我发出哔哔声，最终会断开连接
But
但是
just like a minute ago when you saw it change lanes, when I see the turn signal pop up, I instinctively
就像一分钟前你看到它变道时那样，当我看到转向灯亮起
just want to check, to like make sure that there really isn't a car there. you know,
我会本能地想去确认一下，确保那里真的没有车。你懂的
so I always do that. But, I will say though, that I am more relaxed when the car is driving. And
所以我总是这么做。不过，我得说，当车子在自动驾驶时
I'm more free, if I see something on the side of the road I want to look at, or a building,
我更自由了，如果路边有什么东西吸引我，或是一栋建筑
or you know, whatever, I feel like I'm a little bit more free to take my eyes off the road for
或者说，你知道吗，比起其他时候，我现在可以更自由地把视线从路面移开几秒钟
a few seconds than I would be, likewise if I want to find a song on the infotainment center
同样地，如果我想在车载娱乐系统上找首歌什么的
or something I will. Especially in a situation like this. because of all the driving I've let
特别是在这种情况下。毕竟这辆车经过我所有的驾驶训练
this car do, this situation here is the absolute safest. It is not going to run into that car in
目前这种情况是最安全的，它绝对不会撞上前面那辆车
front of us. that has never happened, that's not going to happen. I'm more worried about
从没发生过，以后也不会发生。我更担心的是
when there's a merge, when there's, when you're in city traffic and you've got all the intersections
当有车辆汇入时，当你在城市交通中遇到各种交叉路口等情况
and stuff. But yeah, when we're just cruising on the highway like this, It's exremely unlikely for
不过确实，像现在这样在高速公路上巡航时，
it to make a mistake. So I do feel a little bit more relaxed to look around and take in
发生意外的可能性极低。所以我确实比平时更放松些，能四处看看
the sights and stuff than I would normally. 15 minutes into the drive, I had yet to touch
风景什么的。开车15分钟后，我还没碰过方向盘或踏板
the wheel or pedals, and Just as I thought he was starting to be more relaxed, when we
就在我以为他开始放松时，当我们驶过第一个高速公路立交桥时，我能看出他又紧张起来了
went over our first highway interchange, I could see he was getting nervous again.
This is wild man, this is very weird. This is. Sometimes there's just no words. I know it. I can
这太奇怪了，有时候真的无话可说
see how nervous you are. I feel like somebody who has been plucked out of the past and dropped into
我能看出你有多紧张。我感觉自己像是被从过去拽出来扔进了未来
the future and my brain is not quite ready for it. I'm still trying to get there because it's,
而我的大脑还没完全准备好。我还在努力适应，因为
there's a lot going on. This is Sunday. Presumably you've driven this in the middle of a weekday,
发生了很多事情。今天是星期天。你大概是在工作日的中午开这车的吧
when it's absolutely brutal. Right now you'd be sitting here in stop and go traffic. So,
当情况变得极其糟糕时。这会儿你本该坐在这里堵在走走停停的车流中。所以
that's actually one of the reasons I said I wanted to do this on a non-rushhour day is,
这实际上也是我说想在一个非高峰日进行的原因之一
not because the car can't handle it, it's just because it would take us 2 hours to
不是因为车不行，而是因为我们要花2个小时才能到达达拉斯
get to Dallas. 2 hours to cover 25 miles. A little over the half way mark, I asked
25英里（约40.2千米）的路要开2小时。刚过一半路程的时候我问
him how he was feeling about the ride so far. But here we are, we're over half way there, it's
他目前对这段骑行的感受如何。但我们已经走到这一步了，路程已过大半
absolutely crushing it. and as you can see I have yet to do anything. I will say it just. We've been
而且你也看到了，我还什么都没做呢。我得说，我们才开了
driving for what, 15 minutes now, and in just 15 minutes I've gone from extremely nervous to only
大概15分钟的车，就在这短短的15分钟里，我从极度紧张变成了
slightly nervous. Which is very impressive. It's absolutely incredible that this is even possible.
只有一点点紧张。这非常令人印象深刻。简直不可思议
If you'd have asked me 15 years ago, I would have said "not in my lifetime." If you had asked me a
如果15年前你问我，我会说“这辈子都看不到”。一年前你问我
year ago, I would have said that. I mean, a year ago I didn't think we were anywhere near this.
我也会这么说。我的意思是，一年前我完全没料到我们离这一步如此之近
Over 30 minutes into drive, we can finally see downtown Dallas in the distance.
开车超过30分钟后，我们终于远远地看到了达拉斯市中心
I really do feel like driverless cars, or at least self-driving cars makes sense. Cause it's,
我真心觉得无人驾驶汽车，或者至少是自动驾驶汽车很有意义。因为
like you said, if you're 85 and you need to go to the store to get groceries, hop in the car
就像你说的，如果你85岁了需要去商店买杂货
and it can take you. It opens up a whole world. Which, I think is awesome. Terrifying.
上车它就能带你去。这打开了一个全新的世界。我觉得这太棒了，但也挺吓人的
But like, I actually feel more comfortable riding in the passenger seat with the self-driving
但说真的，比起让一个刚拿到驾照的15岁孩子开车
driving through this situation than I would with a 15 year old who just got their learner's permit.
我反而更放心坐在自动驾驶汽车的副驾驶上通过这种路况
36 minutes into the drive, as we drove through the mayhem that is downtown traffic,
驾车36分钟后，当我们驶过市区交通的混乱地段时
I posed the question to David.
我把这个问题向大卫提了出来
Well let me ask you. When you see those videos on youtube that says self driving is never going to
让我来问你。当你在YouTube上看到那些声称自动驾驶永远不会成功
work, it doesn't work, it's a big scam, and all of those things. What do you have to say about that now
根本没用、是个大骗局之类的视频时
that we're sitting in downtown Dallas. I have not touched the wheel since we
此刻我们坐在达拉斯市中心，你对此有什么要说的？从离开家门到现在我都没碰过方向盘
left the house. It's very nerve racking. But it is exceedingly capable. This is absolutely wild.
虽然让人神经紧绷，但这车的表现实在出色得离谱。太疯狂了
And I do genuinely think that self-driving will happen. Because, there's enough desire for it to
我真心认为自动驾驶会成为现实。因为人们对它有足够强烈的需求
happen. There's enough people that hate driving. Oh yeah. it makes sense for this to be a thing.
有足够多的人讨厌开车。没错，这件事合情合理
I can't wait for this to be good enough that I can go to sleep. or. Now here's an interesting
迫不及待地希望一切快点好起来，这样我就能去睡觉了。或者，现在遇到个有趣的情况
situation. We're going to go around a guy. Around a guy who's just sitting, with his 4 ways on.
我们得绕过一辆车。绕过那个开着双闪灯、原地停着的车
That's. Of all the things it's done all day, that's probably the most impressive thing,
我觉得在它一整天所做的事情当中，这可能是最令人印象深刻的一件事
I feel like. That ability to be like, there's somebody in this lane that's got their flashers
这条车道上有个人开着双闪灯
going, and we're not going to move soon, so I'll wait until this lane's clear, move over,
我们一时半会儿动不了，所以我会等到这条车道清空后再变道
and move back so I can make my turn. That is. That's like a frightening level of capability to
然后退后一点，好让我转弯。就是这样。这种判断瞬息万变局势的能力
determine a fluid situation. It's even picking up pedestrians walking on the sidewalks over there.
简直惊人。它甚至能识别出那边人行道上行走的路人
And a few minutes later we were just about to be at the destination address.
几分钟后，我们即将到达目的地
There's just so much data to take in. Oooh, it almost tripped it up. But it caught it. That
需要接收的数据实在太多了。哎呀，差点让它绊倒了。不过它及时稳住了
was a dude crossing when he should not have been crossing. I think. There we go, I think it's going
刚才有个家伙在不该过马路的时候闯了过去
to drop us off at this. I went ahead and took over. Ah, I know, it was aiming for this one!
好了，我觉得它要把我们送到这个位置。我抢先接管了控制。我知道了，它原本瞄准的是这个！
ok. That was your fault, not it's fault! Yeah, I hit the break because I thought maybe that was it.
那是你的错，不是它的错！对，我踩了刹车，因为我觉得可能就是这样
So basically what happened was I disengaged FSD because I thought it had passed our parking
简单来说，当时我解除了全自动驾驶模式，误以为已经开过了停车场
garage, when in reality it had not. But overall the drive went well, and honestly exactly how I
实际上还没有。不过整体驾驶过程很顺利，完全符合我的预期
expected it to. As we pulled into the garage, David gave me his final thoughts on the drive.
当车开进车库时，戴维分享了他对这次试驾的最终感想
Unbelievably impressive. I am completely and totally blown away.
难以置信地令人印象深刻。我完全被震撼到了
After we parked, we took a short walk to find the giant eyeball. It certainly wasn't hard
停车后，我们走了一小段路去找那个巨大的眼球雕塑。它确实很显眼
to spot. Unfortunately we couldn't really get close to it because they were doing some sort
一眼就能看到。可惜的是我们没能真正靠近它，因为当时有人
of aerobics class or something in front of it. That seems like an odd place to do that. But
在雕塑前上健美操课之类的活动。选在那地方锻炼似乎有点奇怪。不过
there it is. It's just huge. And it's right in front of this building here.
它真是巨大无比。而且正好就在这栋楼的前面
So, if you're ever going to be in Dallas, here's something else for you to go check out.
所以，如果你有机会到达拉斯，这里还有一样东西值得你去看看
So, I just wanted to mention I suspect there's going to be some people who are going to say
所以，我想提前说明一下，我猜肯定会有人说我伪造了视频
that I faked the video by like editing out all of the times it nearly killed us or something
比如剪掉了所有我们差点丧命的片段之类的
like that. And so, one of the things I did is I left a completely unedited video one
为此，我专门保留了一段完全未剪辑的视频
contiguous like 42 whatever minute clip. It also has all the conversation between me and
一段连续42分钟左右的完整片段，里面还包含我和
David Lovett. We have a a number of interesting conversations about philosophical things like
大卫·洛维特之间的所有对话。我们进行了许多关于哲学问题的有趣对话
the trolley problem and all that kind of stuff. So, if you want to check that out I'm putting a
比如电车难题之类的话题。所以，如果你想了解这些内容
link to that down in the description as well.
我也会在描述中放上相关链接
And so, when I watch these videos like this one for example, by Benn Jordan,
因此，当我看到像本·乔丹制作的这类视频时
which claims that "no, your car will never be able to drive you around"
声称“不，你的车永远无法载着你到处跑”
I find myself confused, wondering if perhaps the last few months were a dream, or a delusion, or what?
我感到困惑，怀疑过去的几个月是否只是一场梦，或是一种幻觉，又或是别的什么？
I'd also like to briefly mention this chart,
我也想简单提一下这张图表
discussing the levels of autonomy. I see it tossed around often when discussing Tesla
在讨论自动驾驶等级时，我经常看到人们提起特斯拉
and many people will point out that Tesla is technically considered #2 on this list.
很多人会指出，从技术层面来说，特斯拉在这份榜单上排名第二
But, let's be realistic. After what you've just seen,
但现实点说，在刚刚目睹这一切之后
I think you can agree that this isn't
我想你会同意这样的安排
a fair placement. It probably has more to do with what something is legally certified for,
并不公平。这很可能与某事物在法律上的认证标准更有关系
rather than what it can really do, because I feel like my Tesla should easily be here at #4.
而不是它真正能做到什么，因为我觉得我的特斯拉应该轻松排在第4位
OK, now that we've seen what it can do, I need to mention a few other things. First of all,
好的，既然我们已经了解了它的功能，我还需要提几点其他事项。首先
I'm currently using FSD version 12.6.4. And my 2022 Tesla is equipped with self driving
我目前使用的是全自动驾驶 12.6.4版本。而我的2022款特斯拉搭载的是
hardware version 3, which came out in 2019 is already obsolete and can't even run the
2019年推出的自动驾驶硬件3.0版本，现在已经过时
latest FSD software. Most shipping Teslas include hardware version 4 these days,
甚至连最新的FSD软件都无法运行。如今大多数出厂的特斯拉都配备了硬件4.0版本
and the new Robotaxi is apparently already on hardware version 5.
而新款Robotaxi显然已经采用了硬件5版本
So, if you thought my car did well on the drive, just imagine how much better
所以，如果你觉得我的车在驾驶中表现不错
the later hardware and software is.
那就想象一下后来的硬件和软件会有多大的提升吧
In fact, now I want to go back and mention the Mark Rober video again. Remember, he was just
事实上，现在我想回过头再提一下马克·罗伯的视频。别忘了
using autopilot for this test. Another youtuber Kyle Paul recently recreated that scenario
他当时只是用自动驾驶功能进行这项测试。另一位视频博主凯尔·保罗最近
using FSD and found that hardware 4 Teslas would actually stop for the Wylie Coyote wall.
用全自动驾驶复现了该场景，发现搭载硬件4.0版本的特斯拉竟然能为威利狼的假墙停下
However, when he tested a hardware 3 Tesla like mine, it did in fact still crash right through it.
然而，当他测试了一台和我一样的特斯拉硬件3版本时，它实际上还是直接穿了过去
Fortunately, this is not a phenomenon people can expect to encounter in the real world.
幸运的是，这并不是人们在现实世界中会遇到的现象
OK, so where does that put Tesla on this scale I created?
好的，那么根据我制定的这个标准，特斯拉处于什么位置？
Well, I think with the current version in my car, I'd put it right here.
嗯，我觉得以我车上现在的版本，我会把它放在这里
Maybe a bit better than a student driver, but not as good as an experienced sober human driver.
或许比学车的新手强点，但比不上经验丰富且清醒的人类驾驶员
And it's possible that the newer versions with hardware 4,
而硬件版本4的新款车型可能
that I can't use in my car may already be at the level of human driver, I'm not sure.
已经达到人类驾驶员的水平，虽然我的车无法使用，这点我并不确定
so, what I want to show you now is this video I captured on my dashcam a few months ago while
所以，我现在想给你们看的是几个月前晚上
driving home from the arcade at night. Notice the Tesla on the right. That's a woman's feet hanging
我从街机厅开车回家时用行车记录仪拍到的这段视频。注意右边那辆特斯拉。有女人的脚从车窗伸出来
out the side of the window. And she looks to me like she's highly intoxicated. Now let's be real,
在我看来她像是醉得不轻。咱们实话实说吧
I'm not in any way, shape, or form, condoning this behavior. You shoudn't be behind the wheel if you
我绝不以任何方式、形式或名义纵容这种行为。酒后驾车绝不可取
are intoxicated. That being said, if you are going to do it anyway, which clearly some people do,
话虽如此，如果你执意要这么做，显然有些人确实如此
you're actually better off letting the Tesla do the driving. In the case of this woman,
你其实让特斯拉自动驾驶会更好。就这位女士的情况而言
it's probably for the best that she is letting her car do the driving.
她让车子自动驾驶可能是最好的选择
Okay, so let's be real for a moment. The car doesn't always do everything right. And so,
好吧，咱们实话实说。这辆车并不总是完美无缺。所以，
I wanted to be as objective as possible. And so, I've got a collection of dash cam clips
我力求尽可能客观。因此，我收集了一些行车记录仪片段
that I want to show you. Now some of these clips show the car doing amazingly well in edge case scenarios.
想展示给大家。其中有些片段展现了这辆车在极端场景下的卓越表现
Some of these clips show the car making mistakes. Let's take a look at some of these.
其中一些片段展示了车辆犯错的情况。我们来看看其中几个例子
In this situation, there was a 4-way stop and I was turning left. I pulled up right
这种情况下，有一个四向停车路口，我正要左转
as the other cars were taking off, then the Tesla decided it was its turn. So,
就在其他车辆起步时我也刚好驶出，结果特斯拉却判定该它通行了。于是
I do think the other cars had right away, but it was such a close call, I had to watch the
我确实认为其他车辆当时拥有路权，但情况太过接近
footage myself to be sure who was in the wrong.
我不得不自己查看录像才能确定是谁的过错
In this case, I was driving a night through a
当时我正夜间驾车
construction zone and a cat ran across the road. It's a bit hard to see in the video,
经过施工区域，突然有只猫窜过马路。视频里可能看得不太清楚
but the car actually slammed on the breaks to avoid hitting the cat,
但车子实际上猛踩刹车以避免撞到那只猫
so that's one definitely in favor of the car. This is an example of where I had to take control.
所以这绝对是有利于汽车的一点。这是我不得不掌控局面的一个例子
There was a motocycle wreck that had just occurred in front of me. And the turn lane was blocked,
在我面前刚刚发生了一起摩托车事故。转弯车道被堵住了
so the car stopped. The car would have basically stayed here indefinitely until the blockage was clear.
于是车停了下来。基本上，这辆车会一直停在这里，直到障碍被清除
Fortunately I was able to take over and maneuver around. I wouldn't even call
幸好我能接手并操控绕行。这甚至称不上
this a safety issue, but if it were a robotaxi and you were a passenger, you'd be annoyed.
安全问题，但如果是无人驾驶出租车而你作为乘客，肯定会感到不爽
So in this video, the car on my left starts drifting over into my lane. Since there was
在这段视频中，我左侧的车辆开始向我的车道漂移。由于
nobody in the lane on the other side, the car took action and moved partially into that lane to avoid
另一侧车道没有其他车辆，这辆车采取了行动，部分驶入那条车道以避免事故
an accident. So, another one in favor of the car.
所以，这又是车辆表现优异的一个例子
Here's an interesting one. There's road
这有个有趣的情况。道路施工中
construction and the cones force us into the wrong side of the road. The Tesla does a good
锥筒把我们逼到了错误的车道上。特斯拉
job at following the cones and everything. But, the trouble is, see the light turns red. And
在跟随锥筒方面做得不错。但问题是，你看红灯亮了。而且
after a moment the car decides to just go, most likely because it doesn't realize the light being
片刻之后，车子决定自行启动，很可能是因为它没意识到右侧那盏灯的信号
way over to the right applies to us. So I had to hit the breaks to stop it. Now, to be fair,
是针对我们的。所以我不得不踩刹车让它停下。公平地说
this isn't really a safety issue because the car knew that there was no other traffic. It wouldn't
这其实不算安全问题，因为车辆知道当时没有其他车。它不会
have pulled out into another car. But I could have gotten a ticket for running a red light.
驶入另一辆车的路径。但我可能会因为闯红灯而收到罚单
Here's another situation. I took this on my iPhone. The traffic lights were malfunctioning,
这是另一个场景。我用iPhone拍的。当时交通信号灯失灵了
but the car seemed to know exactly what to do, and treated it just like a 4-way stop.
但这辆车似乎很清楚该怎么做，就像对待一个四向停车标志一样
These unusual, unexpected type situations are exaclt the sort of thing that I worried about with
这些出乎意料、非同寻常的情况正是我对自动驾驶汽车所担忧的
self-driving cars. But in most cases, the car has handled them like a champ.
但在大多数情况下，车辆都能像冠军一样应对自如
I have also used FSD in the rain with no problem. But I have not used it in a heavy thunderstorm
我也曾在雨天使用FSD功能，完全没有问题。但还没在强烈雷暴天气中尝试过
yet. So I'm not sure how it would behave there. And since I live in Texas it may be another few
所以不确定它在那种情况下的表现。由于我住在得克萨斯州
years before I can try driving in snow. here's a bizarre situation. I'm not sure
可能还要等上几年才有机会体验雪地驾驶。这真是种奇怪的境遇，我也说不准
what the heck has happened here. There is debris in the left lane of the freeway, even an whole
这里到底发生了什么。高速公路的左车道上散落着碎片
tire and wheel, although doesn't seem to have come from the stopped vehicle in front. Anyway,
甚至还有一整个轮胎和轮毂，虽然看起来不像是从前方的停驶车辆上掉下来的。不管怎样
Smurf sees this junk and does indeed stop for it and merge into traffic like a champ.
蓝精灵看到这堆垃圾，果然停了下来，像个冠军一样融入了车流
And here I want to show what is honestly the worst problem that FSD has, at least with the
在这里我想展示的，坦率地说，是全自动驾驶目前最严重的问题
version I have. Sometimes when a lane is going to end, the car is not proactive enough in getting over.
至少在我使用的版本中如此。当车道即将结束时，车辆在变道时表现得不够主动
And when that happens, sometimes it is too late because there is too much traffic,
而当这种情况发生时，有时已经为时过晚，因为交通太过拥堵
or sometimes it just keeps going right over the bumps like in this case. I did take the
有时它会直接碾过减速带，就像这次一样
wheel and force it into the other lane. But I'd like to think it would have stopped before
我确实握住方向盘强行变道了。但我想它应该会在撞上路沿前停下
hitting that curb. But we'll never know for sure.
不过我们永远无法确定
So, I want to break down my presonal experience
因此，我想将我的个人经历分解成一个饼图
into a pie chart showing the various reasons I've had to intervene.
展示我不得不干预的各种原因
I can easily say, beyond any doubt that at least 75% of these
我可以毫不犹豫地说，至少有75%的情况
have been due to a disagreement between me and the map.
是由于我和地图之间的意见不合造成的
So, let me give you an example of what I mean about route disagreements. Let's say the route
那么，让我举个关于路线分歧的例子来说明我的意思
shows you're about to exit the freeway, and then get right back on. Now, that's fine, for example,
假设导航显示你即将驶出高速，然后立刻重新驶入。这种情况在某些情况下是合理的，比如
if there is an obvious backup on the freeway. But I'm sure anyone that uses GPS has seen examples
如果高速公路上有明显的拥堵。但我确信任何使用GPS的人
of this where clearly there is no backup on the freeway. At least not any more. So in a
都见过这样的情况，明明高速上已经不再拥堵了。所以
case like that, I intervene and make it stay on the freeway. So, this is just one example,
遇到这种情况，我会介入并确保它留在高速公路上。所以，这只是其中一个例子
but things like this definitely represent the bulk of the interventions I've had to do,
但这类事情无疑占据了我不得不进行干预的大部分情况
and even if i didn't intervene, it isn't really a problem that I would consider dangerous, its just annoying.
即便我不插手干预，这也不是什么我认为会构成危险的问题，只是有点烦人罢了
Here's another great example. There is this spot where going southbound, 820 splits off into 121.
这里还有一个很好的例子。在某个地点，向南行驶时，820号公路会分岔出121号公路
Well, in the past to stay on 820 meant being in the right lanes. But after some recent
过去，要在820号公路上行驶意味着要走右边的车道。但经过最近的施工后
construction, it is now switched. And now you need to be in the left lane. It took nearly
情况发生了变化。现在你需要走左边的车道
6 months for the map to be updated to reflect this, so the car always wanted to take the wrong
地图花了近6个月的时间才更新以反映这一变化，因此汽车总是想走错车道
lane. Thus, I would always have to intervene.
所以我总是不得不进行干预
So the question is, imagining for a moment that this happened in a driverless car,
所以问题是，假设这种情况发生在一辆无人驾驶汽车上
either whether it be literally a car with no humans in it,
不论是字面意思上的一辆没有人的汽车
or whether it be a like a robo taxi or something like that.
或者它是否像机器人出租车之类的东西
Well, it's not an inherently dangerous
这不是一个本质上危险的问题
problem It just took a wrong turn. And so, it would obviously reroute with GPS just like
只是走错了路。所以，它显然会像 GPS 对人类司机那样重新规划路线
just like GPS does with a human driver when you take a wrong turn. So, it's not inherently dangerous.
当你走错路时，GPS 就会这么做。因此，这并非本质上存在危险
It just might be annoying, especially if you're like a passenger in a taxi or something like that
这可能会很烦人，尤其是当你像出租车乘客之类的时候
Also along these lines, the navigation will often decide it wants to take the express lane.
沿着这些思路，导航系统还经常会决定要走快速车道
And I don't mind paying for that if there's a terrible backup on the main highway. But I don't want to
如果主干道堵得水泄不通，我不介意为此付费
pay like 5 bucks just to save 30 seconds. So, often I'll take over to avoid getting on the
但我不愿意为了省30秒就花5块钱。所以，如果觉得不值
express lane if I don't think it is worth it.
我通常会选择变道避开快速车道
So, another related problem I have experienced
所以，我遇到的另一个相关问题是
is this rural highway that I drive on every now and then. And the car wants to stop here in order
这条我时不时会行驶的乡村公路。车子需要在这里停下来
to make a right turn. And this is exactly correct. It's exactly what the car is supposed to do.
以便右转，这完全正确。这正是车子应该做的
But, all the local people line up down the shoulder and use it as a turn lane, even though it isn't marked
但是，所有当地人都在路肩排队，把它当作转弯车道使用
as such and is probably technically illegal. This ends up blocking my car from being able to make
尽管那里并没有这样的标记，严格来说可能属于违法行为。这最终导致我的车
the correct, legal right turn. Now, right now, the city probably doesn't care. But if there were more
无法进行正确且合法的右转。目前，市政府大概对此并不在意。但如果情况变得更加严重
autonomous cars on the road and this started to be more of a problem, then the city might come out
自动驾驶汽车上路后，这个问题开始变得更为突出，届时市政部门
and restripe the road like this in oder to make that a proper turn lane. And this brings to me
可能会重新规划道路标线，就像这样设置专门的转弯车道
to another point. I think once autonomous cars reach a certain tipping point, cities will begin
这让我想到另一个观点，我认为一旦自动驾驶汽车达到某个临界点，城市管理
to address issues like this, which will actually improve the operation of the cars,
将着手解决此类问题，而这实际上会提升车辆的运行效率
even without needing to improve the cars themselves. To use an analogy from computing history.
甚至无需改进汽车本身。借用计算机历史上的一个类比
There was this clone of the Apple II called the Laser 128. And it was only like 95% compatible.
有一款名为Laser 128的苹果II克隆机，但它的兼容性只有大约95%
But the computer was extremely popular, and once sales reached a certain point,
但电脑极其受欢迎，一旦销量达到某个点
software companies started testing their software with the Laser to ensure compatibility. Thus,
软件公司开始用Laser测试他们的软件以确保兼容性。因此，
the laser became even more compatible after a few years, even though the computer itself
几年后，Laser变得更加兼容了，尽管电脑本身没有改变
didn't change. And so, yeah, I think we're going to see this a lot with cities and road planning.
所以，是的，我认为我们会在城市和道路规划中看到很多这样的情况
So, back to my pie chart. The next 20% of reasons for me intervening would be what I call preventing
回到我的饼图。接下来的20%干预原因，我称之为
annoyance to other drivers. For example, sometimes the car will be going too slow or
防止其他驾驶者感到烦躁。例如，有时车辆会开得太慢或太快
too fast. Sometimes it wants to change lanes, only to change right back again. And believe it or not,
有时它刚想变道，结果又立刻变回来。信不信由你
this is also related to map problems most of the time. I've already determined that there
这大多时候也与地图问题相关。我已经确认车辆
is more than one map or data set the car relies on. And here's some proof of this.
依赖的地图或数据集不止一个。以下是证明这一点的部分证据
There's a bridge near my house that was recently built and they moved the whole road over about a 100 feet
我家附近有座新修的桥，他们把整条路往一侧挪了大约100英尺（约30.5米）
to one side. Notice that the blue line represents the course the car has plotted to drive.
注意蓝线代表车辆规划行驶的路线
But the white line is the actual road. And clearly they don't match up. So the navigation is plotting
但白线才是实际道路。显然它们并不吻合。因此导航系统
a course based on one map, and displaying the graphics based on a more updated map.
正基于一张地图规划路线，却根据更新后的地图显示图形
So I believe erroneous map data is probably the number one reason for the car to do weird things
因此我认为错误的地图数据可能是导致车辆做出奇怪行为的主要原因
like changing over to a lane only to change right back again or just suddenly breaking for
比如突然变道后又立刻变回来，或是无故急刹
no reason. In fact there was a construction zone recently where the speed limit had been reduced to
最近有一处施工区域限速降至
55 mph. And even after that construction zone had been removed and the speed limit restored, the car
55英里/小时(约89km/h)即便该施工区已撤除且限速恢复，车辆依然
still believed it was 55 miles an hour every time it would enter this spot, thus hitting the brakes.
每次经过这个地点时，仍以为限速是每小时55英里，于是猛踩刹车
And, it took months for that to be resolved. And I know these are map related problems because they
而且，解决这个问题花了几个月时间。我知道这些都是与地图相关的问题
always happen in exactly the same place.
因为它们总是发生在完全相同的地点
And while these behaviors aren't neccessarily dangerous,
尽管这些行为不一定危险
they are annoying, especially to other drivers on the road,
但它们确实令人恼火，尤其对路上的其他司机来说更是如此
so when that sort of thing happens, I intervene. So the last 5% of the interventions I would say
所以当发生这类情况时，我会介入。可以说最后5%的干预
are for safety reasons. Over the last 4 months that I've been using the system,
是出于安全考虑。在过去4个月使用这套系统的过程中
I've probably had to take over maybe 3 or 4 times for what I perceived as a safety issue.
我大概有3、4次因为觉得存在安全隐患而不得不接手
And there's no guarantee there would have been a crash had I not, but I wasn't willing to take the risk.
虽然不能确定如果我不这么做就一定会发生碰撞，但我不愿冒这个险
The majority of these cases have been related to merging into traffic when the lane I am in
这些案例中的大多数都与当前车道即将结束时并入车流有关
comes to an end. The car often waits until the last minute to merge. Interestingly enough,
车辆往往等到最后一刻才进行变道。有趣的是
in some states that is actually the law and it's called zipper merge. But we don't do that
在某些州这确实是法律规定，被称为“拉链式并道”。但在德克萨斯我们
in Texas. In fact, it's considered rude here to wait until the lane ends to merge and often
不这么做。事实上，在这里等到车道尽头才并线会被视为粗鲁行为
people refuse to let you in. And this has been the most common safety related issue I've encountered.
人们通常拒绝让你插队。这是我遇到的最常见的安全相关问题
Okay so I just got some final thoughts I want to talk about before we wrap up this video
好的，在彻底结束这个视频之前，我还有几点最后的想法要聊聊
completely. So there's probably going to be some people asking like that trip I took to Dallas and
可能会有人问起我去达拉斯的那趟旅行
there was you know I touched nothing like I I did nothing from the time we left my driveway to the
你们知道的，从我们离开我家车道到抵达达拉斯这段时间里，我什么都没碰，什么都没做
time we got to Dallas. And people are going to ask like "is that normal or was that an anomaly?"
大家肯定会好奇：“这算正常情况还是反常现象？”
And the truth is, that's actually pretty normal. I mean, I don't drive to downtown Dallas very often,
而事实上，这种情况其实相当普遍。我是说，我平时也不怎么开车去达拉斯市中心
but I do drive to the arcade like four or five times a week and that's a half hour drive each
不过我确实每周会开车去游戏厅四五次，单程大概半小时
direction and I almost always let the car drive and very rarely do I have to do anything. So yeah,
几乎每次都让车子自动驾驶，很少需要我手动操作。所以确实
in fact I've gone through a number of emotional stages with FSD So the first couple of weeks
我对FSD经历了多个情感阶段。最初几周
I started using it back in 2024 I was a nervous wreck Uh kind of like David Lovett was in in the
就是2024年刚开始使用时，我紧张得要命，就像你在视频里看到的大卫·洛维特那样
video that you saw. But, after a couple weeks I kind of got used to that and started to trust it
但几周后我逐渐适应了，开始对它有了更多信任
a bit more. And then I was just for the next few weeks I was just kind of in this state of awe when
接下来的几周里，我几乎一直处于一种惊叹的状态中
I was driving I would just be looking around like "This is amazing I'm in the future I can't believe it."
开车时，我会环顾四周，心想：“太不可思议了，我竟然生活在未来，简直难以置信。”
You know and all this kind of stuff And then uh after a few weeks of that I just got to where
你知道的，就是这类事情。然后，几周之后我就习以为常了
it was just commonplace. Now I'm you know looking around like why isn't everybody using this? This
现在我就觉得，为什么不是所有人都在用这个呢？
is this is just how I get around now you know. So that that's kind of the stage that I'm in now.
这就是我现在出行的方式，你懂的。所以这就是我目前所处的阶段
And, in fact I wanted to mention that sometimes I feel like I'm in the Harry Potter universe because
事实上，我想说的是，有时我感觉自己仿佛置身于《哈利·波特》的世界里
it's like I'm willing to bet there's probably a lot of drivers that don't even realize my car is
因为我敢打赌，很多司机看到我的车
electric when they see it going down the road. But I'm willing to bet 99.9% of drivers that see my
在路上行驶时，甚至都没意识到它是电动的。但我更敢肯定，99.9%的司机看到我的车时
car have no idea that my car is driving itself and that I'm basically just a passenger in the car.
根本不知道它正在自动驾驶，而我基本上只是车上的乘客而已
So, I can kind of say it's almost like I am a wizard driving down the road and everyone else is
所以，我可以说这感觉就像我是个巫师在路上开车
a muggle. They're just completely oblivious to the fact. So a couple other things I wanted to
而其他人都是麻瓜。他们完全没意识到这一点。还有几件事我想提一下
mention So first of all uh I discovered quite by accident one day that if I set FSD if I enable it
首先，有一天我偶然发现，如果我不设定路线就直接启用全自动驾驶，它仍然会启动
without setting a course it still enables It still goes And I discovered this uh one day and I was
并继续行驶。那天我发现了这一点
driving or letting the car drive around and I was like wonder why it's going this
当时我正开车或者说让车自己行驶，我就想它为什么要往这边走
way And it took a weird turn and then it took another and I'm like where where is it going
它拐了个奇怪的弯，然后又拐了一个，我就想它到底要去哪儿
And so I looked down at the map to see like where it had plotted to go And then I realized I never
于是我低头看了看地图，想看看它规划了怎样的路线，然后才意识到
set a course It's just driving randomly And so one of these days when I get a little time I want to
我根本没设定目的地，它只是在随机行驶。所以等哪天有空了
set the camera back up in the car and just turn on FSD and just see like where does it go? Does it go
我想重新在车里架好摄像头，打开全自动驾驶功能，看看它究竟会开往哪里。它会去哪儿呢？
home Like it's factory? you know I don't know, I I'm I'm curious to figure out where it goes given
它会像出厂设置一样回家吗？你知道我不清楚，我很好奇想弄明白
no instructions. And of course I got one more thing I'm going to say if people even make it
在没有指令的情况下它会去哪儿。当然我还有件事要说，如果真有人能看到视频这里的话
this far in the video is I'm sure there's going to be a ton of people in the comments saying that I
我敢肯定评论区会有一堆人说我
doxed myself And I know because I've gone through this like dozens and dozens of times already And
自曝隐私了。我知道，因为我已经经历过几十次甚至上百次了
because yeah you can see where I live by tracing back the route that we took or just
你可以通过追溯我们走过的路线或者
look up my license plate number or whatever And the reality is I was just going to say my
直接查我的车牌号之类的方式找到我住的地方。实际上，我正想说
address has never been a secret It isn't a secret now and it has never been a secret And so so you
我的地址从来就不是秘密，现在不是，也从来都不是
might say "Well David how come you cover up your your addresses in a video?" And and the actual
你可能会问：“大卫，那为什么你在视频里要遮住你的地址呢？”其实
reason that I do that is just so people won't bug me so much because every time I've shown
我这么做的真正原因，只是不想被大家过度打扰。因为每次
my address I get like a thousand emails and a thousand comments in the comments section I've
我公开地址后，总会收到上千封邮件和评论区铺天盖地的留言
even had people text me and call me at like 3:00 in the morning telling me "David you've
甚至有人凌晨三点发短信打电话警告我
doxed yourself! You've got to take that video down." And I'm like that it the address was
“大卫你泄露个人信息了！快删掉视频。”但其实这个地址
never a secret to begin with So so if you were getting ready to run to your keyboard to tell me
从来就不是什么秘密。所以如果你正准备敲键盘提醒我地址暴露了
原标题：Self-Driving Car？ Does it Work？! 原作者：The 8-Bit Guy
that I have revealed my address then please just don't worry about it Uh it's it's not an issue So
真的不必费心，这根本不是问题
原视频上传日期：2025年4月25日
anyway I think that actually wraps it up for this episode. So, as always thanks for watching!
好了，这期内容就到这里吧。一如既往感谢大家的观看！
翻译/压制/字幕制作：HAF半个水果
翻译质量权威评价：原来25年就有小拉即用机翻糊弄人了
向所有字幕制作及相关人员道一声辛苦了 (*ˊᗜˋ*)/ᵗᑋᵃᐢᵏ ᵞᵒᵘ*
感谢字幕组的默默耕耘，你们的每一行字都能让更多人能够跨越语言障碍，享受精彩的内容
字幕制作不易，喜欢的话支持一下我吧！到YouTube上关注原作者！